Okay, here's the last lecture in the
chapter on
orthogonality. So, we met orthogonal
vectors, two
vectors. We met orthogonal
subspaces like the row space and null
space. Now today we meet an orthogonal
basis and an orthogonal matrix. So we
really this is this chapter cleans up
orthogonality and really I want to I
should use the word
orthonormal. Ortho orthogonal is so my
vectors are Q1 Q2 up to QN. Can can I lo
use the letter Q here for to to remind
me I'm talking about orthogonal
things not just any vectors but
orthogonal ones. So what does that mean?
That means that every Q is orthogonal to
every other Q. It's a natural idea to
have a basis that's got that's headed
off at 90° angles. The inner products
are all zero. Of course, if Q is
certainly QI is not orthogonal to
itself, but there we'll make the the
best choice again. Make it a unit
vector. Then Q transpose Qi is one for a
unit vector. The length squared is one
and that's what I would use the word
normal. So ortho for this part, normal
normalized unit length for this part.
Okay. So, first part of the lecture
is how does having an orthonormal basis
make things nice? It certainly does. It
makes all the calculations better. A
whole lot of numerical linear algebra is
built around working
with orthonormal vectors because they
never get out of hand. They never
overflow or underflow.
and I'll put them into a matrix Q and
then the second part of the lecture will
be suppose my basis my my columns of A
are not orthonormal how do I make them
so and the two names associated with
that simple idea are Graham and Schmidt
so the first part
is we've got a basis like this let's put
those let's put those into the columns
of a matrix
So an so uh so a matrix
Q that has or I'll put these orthonormal
vectors q1 will be the first column qn
will be the the nth
column and I want to
say I want to write this property
qranspose
qj being zero I want to put
that in a matrix form and just the right
thing is to look at qranspose q. So this
chapter has been looking at a transpose
a so it's natural to look at qranspose q
and the beauty is it comes out perfectly
because
qranspose has these vectors in its rows.
The first row is q1 transpose. The nth
row is qn transpose. So that's
qranspose. And now I want to multiply by
q that has q1 along to qn in the
columns. That's q. And what do I get?
You really this is the first simplest
most basic fact that how do orthonormal
vectors orthonormal columns in a
matrix what happens if I compute
qranspose
q? Do you see it? If I take the first
row times the first column, what do I
get? A one. If I take the first row
times the second column, what do I get?
zero. That's the orthogonality. The
first row times the last column is zero.
And so I'm getting ones on the
diagonal and I'm getting zeros
everywhere else. I'm getting the
identity
matrix. You see how that's it's just
like the right calculation to do. If you
have orthonor orthonormal columns and
the matrix doesn't have to be square
here.
We might have just two
columns and they might have four lots of
components. So, but they're
orthonormal. And when we do qranspose
time q that qranspose time q or
aranspose a just asks for all those
dotproducts
rows times columns. And in this
orthonormal case we get the best
possible answer of the identity. Okay.
So this is this is like so I mean now
now we have a new bunch of important
matrices. What have we seen previously?
We've seen in the in the distant past we
had triangular matrices, diagonal
matrices, permutation
matrices. That was early chapters. Then
we had row echelon
forms. Then uh in this chapter we've
already seen projection
matrices. And now we're seeing this new
class of matrices with orthonormal
columns. That's a very long expression.
I am sorry that I can't just call them
orthogonal matrices.
But that word orthogonal matrices or or
maybe I should be able to call it
orthonormal matrices. Why don't we call
it orthonormal matrices? Let I mean that
would be an absolutely perfect name for
Q call it an orthonormal matrix because
its columns are orthonormal. Okay. But
the convention is that we only use that
name orthogonal matrix. We only use
this this word orthogonal. We don't even
say orthonormal for some unknown reason
matrix when it's
square. So in this in the case when this
is a square
matrix that's the case we call it an
orthogonal matrix. And what's what's
special about the case when it's square?
when it's a square
matrix, we've got its
inverse. So, so in the case if
q is
square then
q transpose q = i tells us let me write
that underneath tells
us that
qranspose is q
inverse. There we have the easy to
remember property for a
square matrix with orthonormal columns
that I I need to write some examples
down. Let's see
uh some examples like if I take any
permutation some examples let's do some
examples any permutation matrix let me
take just some random permutation matrix
permutation Q equals let's say I'll make
it 3x3 say 0 0 1 1 0 0 1 0
Okay, that certainly
has unit vectors in its columns. Those
vectors are certainly perpendicular to
each
other. And if I figure and so that's it.
That makes it a Q. And if I multip if I
took its transpose, if I multiplied by
qranspose, shall I do that? Let me stick
in qranspose here just to do that
multiplication once more. Transpose
it'll put the put make that into a
column. Make that into a column. Make
that into a column. And the transpose is
also a another Q another orthonormal
matrix. And when I multiply that product
I get I. Okay. So there's an example.
And actually there's a second example.
But those are real easy examples, right?
I mean to get orthogonal matric
orthogonal columns by just putting ones
in different places is like too uh easy.
So let me keep going with examples. So
here's another simple example. Cos theta
sin
theta. There's a unit vector. Oh, let me
even take it. Well, yeah. cos theta sin
theta and now the other way I want sin
theta cos theta but I want the inner
product to be zero and if I put a minus
there it'll do it so the that's a unit
vector that's a unit vector and if I
take the dotproduct I get minus plus
zero okay for so for example uh Q equals
equals say 1 one one minus
one. Is that an orthogonal
matrix? I've got orthogonal columns
there, but it's not quite an orthogonal
matrix. How shall I fix it to be an
orthogonal
matrix? Well, what's the length of those
column vectors? The dotproduct with
themselves is right now it's two, right?
the the length
squared the length squared would be 1 +
1 would be two the length would be
square<unk> of two so I better divide by
square<unk> of two
okay so there's a there now I have got
an orthogonal matrix in fact it's this
one when when theta is pi
over4 the cosiness and s well almost I
guess the minus sign is down there so
maybe I don't know maybe minus p<unk>
over4 or
it.
Okay. Uh let me do one final example
just to show that you can get bigger
ones. Uh Q equals let me take that
matrix up in the corner and I'll sort of
repeat that
pattern. Repeat it
again and then minus it down here.
That's one of the world's
favorite orthogonal
matrices. I hope I got it right. Is can
you see
whether if I take the inner product of
one column with another one? Let's see.
If I take the inner product of that
column with that, I have two minuses and
two pluses. That's good. When I take the
inner product of that with that, I have
a plus and a minus. A minus and a plus.
Good. I think it all works out. And what
do I have to divide by now to make those
into unit
vectors? Right now there's those the
vector 1111 has length
two square root of four. So I have to
divide by two to make it unit vector. So
there's another that's my entire array
of simple examples. This this
uh th this construction is named after a
guy called Adamar. And
uh we know how to do it for for 2
4 16 64 and so on. But uh we nobody
knows which exactly which size matrices
have which size which sizes allow
orthogonal matrices of ones and minus
ones. So a atom matrix is an orthogonal
matrix that's got ones and minus ones
and lot of ones some we know some other
sizes there couldn't be a 5x5 I think
but there are some sizes that nobody yet
knows whether there could be or can't be
uh a matrix like that okay you see those
orthogonal
matrices
Now let me ask what why is it good to
have orthogonal matrices? What
calculation is made
easy if I have an orthogonal matrix and
and let me let me remember that the
matrix could be rectangular. Shall I put
down a rect I better put a rectangular
example down. So these were all square
examples. Can I put down just a a
rectangular one just to be sure that we
realize that this is possible? Uh let's
help me out. Let's see if I put like a
um a one
two
and minus 2 -1
2. That's an or that's an that's a
matrix. Oh, it's columns aren't
normalized yet. I always have to
remember to do that. I always do that
last because it's easy to do. What
what's the length of those columns? So,
if I wanted them if I wanted them to be
length 1, I should divide by their
length, which is So, I look at 1 2 + 2^2
+ 2^ 2 that's 1 and 4 and 4 is 9. So, I
take the square root and I need to
divide by
three. Okay. So there
is well without that I've got one
orthonormal vector. I mean just one unit
vector. Now put that guy in. Now I have
a basis for the column space for a
two-dimensional
space an orthonormal basis. Right? These
two columns are orthonormal.
They would be an orthonormal basis for
this two-dimensional space that they
span. Orthonormal B vectors, by the way,
have got to be independent. It's easy to
show that orthonormal
vectors, since they're headed off at all
at 90°, there's no combination that
gives zero. Uh now if I wanted
to create now a third one
uh I
could either just put in some third
vector that was independent and go to
this Graham
Schmidt calculation that I'm going to
explain or I could be inspired and say
look that with that pattern why not put
a one in there and a two in there and a
two in there and try to fix up the signs
so that they
worked.
H I don't I don't know if I've done this
too
brilliantly. Uh how let's see what signs
that's minus. Maybe I'd like a minus
sign there. How would that be? Um yeah,
maybe that works.
I think that those three columns are
orthonormal
and they the beauty of this this is the
last example I'll probably find where
there's no square root the the punishing
thing in Graham Schmidt maybe we better
know that in advance is that because I
want these vectors to be unit vectors
I'm always running into square roots.
I'm always dividing by lengths and those
lengths are square roots. So you'll see
as soon as I do a Graham Schmidt
example, square roots are going to show
up. But here are some examples where we
did it without any square root.
Okay. Okay.
So So great. Now next question is what's
the what's the good of having a Q? what
what form what formulas become easier
suppose I want to project so suppose Q
suppose Q has orthonormal
columns I'm I'm I'm using the letter Q
to mean this I'll write it this this one
more time but but I always
mean when I write a Q I always mean that
it has orthonormal columns so
suppose I want to
project
onto its column
space. So what's the projection
matrix? What's the projection matrix if
I project onto a column space? Okay,
that gives me a chance to review the
projection
section, including that big formula,
which used to be have four those four
A's in a row, but now it's got Q's
because I'm projecting onto the column
space of Q. So, do you remember what it
was? It's
Q qranspose Q
inverse QRPOSE.
That's my four Q's in a
row. But what's good
here? What what makes this formula nice?
If I'm projecting onto a column onto a
column space, when I have orthonormal
basis for that space, what makes it nice
is this is the identity. I don't have to
do any inversion. I just get QQRpose.
So QQRpose is a projection matrix. Oh, I
can't help I can't resist just checking
the properties. What what are the
properties of a projection
matrix? There there are two properties
to know for for any projection matrix.
And I'm saying that this is the right
projection matrix when we've got this
orthonormal basis in the
columns. Okay. So there's the projection
matrix. Suppose the matrix is
square. First just tell me first this
extreme case. If if my matrix is square
and it's got these orthonormal columns,
then what's the column
space? If I have a square
matrix and I have independent columns
and even orthonormal columns, then the
column space is the whole space, right?
And what's the projection matrix onto
the whole
space? The identity
matrix. If I'm projecting in the whole
space, I every every vector B is right
where it's supposed to be and I don't
have to move it by projection. So this
would be this will be I this is this is
I'll put in parenthesis this is I if Q
is
square well that we we said that already
if Q if q is square that's the case
where qranspose is q inverse we can put
it on the right we can put it on the
left we always get the identity matrix
if it's
square. But if it's not a square
matrix, then it's
not we don't get the identity matrix. We
this we have QQ
qranspose and just again what are those
two properties of a projection matrix?
First of all, it's
symmetric. Okay, no problem. That's
certainly a symmetric matrix. So what's
that second property of a projection
that if you project and project again
you don't move the second time. So the
other property of a projection matrix
should be that
QQRpose
twice should be the same as QQRpose
once. That's projection matrices. And
that property better fall out right away
because from from the from the fact we
know about orthonormal matrices
qranspose q is i. Okay, you see it in
the middle here is sitting qq qranspose
q. Sorry, that's what I meant to say.
Qranspose q is i. So that's sitting
right in the middle. That cancels out to
give the identity. We're left with one
qur transpose and we're all set. Okay,
so this is the projection
matrix. All the all the
uh equation all the messy equations of
this chapter become trivial
when our matrix when we have this
orthonormal basis. I mean what do I mean
by all the equations? Well, the most
important equation was the normal
equation. You remember old aranspose a
xhat equals arpose
b. But
now, now a is
q. Now I'm thinking I have
qranspose q xhat equals qranspose
b. And what's good about that?
What's good is that matrix on the left
side is the
identity. The matrix on the left is the
identity qranspose q. Normally it isn't.
Normally it's that matrix of inner
products and you've got to compute all
those dopey inner products and and and
solve the system. Here the inner
products are all one or zero. This is
the identity matrix. It's gone. And
there's the answer. There's no inversion
involved. Each component of X is a Q *
B. What what that what that equation is
saying is that the E component is the E
basis vector times B. That's the that's
the
simple that's probably the most
important formula in in uh some major
parts of mathematics that if we have
orthonormal
basis then the
component in the in the ice along the I
the projection on the ice basis vector
is just qranspose b that that that that
that that number x that we look for is
is just a
dotproduct.
Okay. Okay.
So I'm ready now for the sort of like
second half of the lecture
where we don't start with an orthogonal
matrix or orthonormal vectors. We just
start with independent vectors and we
want to make them
orthonormal. So I'm going to Can I do
that now? Now here comes Graham Schmidt.
So So Graham
Schmidt. So this is a
calculation. I won't say I can't quite
say it's like
uh elimination.
because it's it's different. Our our
goal isn't triangular anymore with
elimination. Our goal was make the
matrix
triangular. Now our goal is make the
matrix or orthogonal. Make those columns
orthonormal. So let me start with two
columns. So I start with vectors A and
B and they're just like here. Let me
draw them. Here's
A. Here's
B. For for example, A isn't specially
horizontal. Wasn't meant to be. Just A
is one vector, B is another. I want to
produce th those two vectors. They might
be in 12dimensional space or they might
be in two-dimensional space. They're
independent anyway. So I I I I better be
sure I say that I start with independent
vectors. And I want to produce out of
that Q1 and Q2. I want to produce
orthonormal
vectors. and Graham and
Schmidt, tell me how. Okay. Well,
actually, you could tell me how. I We
don't need, frankly, I don't know.
There's only one idea
here. If Graham had the
idea. Uh I don't know what Schmidt did,
but uh uh Okay, let's You'll see it. You
We don't need either of them, actually.
Okay. So, what am I going to do? I'll
take that this first guy.
Okay. Well, he's
fine. That direction is fine except
Yeah, I I'll say okay, I'll settle for
that direction. So, I I'm going to I'm
going to get So, what am I going my goal
is? I'm going to get orthogonal
vectors and I'll call those capital A
and B. So that's the key step is to get
from any two vectors to two orthogonal
vectors. And then at the end, no
problem. I'll get orthonormal
vectors. How will what will th those
will be my Q's Q1 and Q2. And what will
they be?
Once I've got A and B orthogonal, well,
look, it's no big deal. Maybe that's
what Schmidt
did. He brilliant Schmidt thought, okay,
divide by the length. All right, that's
Schmidt's contribution.
Okay, but Graham had a little more
thinking to do, right? We haven't done
Graham's
part. This part except Okay, I'm happy
with a a can be a that that first
direction is fine. Why should no
complaint about that? The trouble is the
second direction is not fine because
it's
not orthogonal to the first. I'm looking
for a
vector that's starts with
B but makes it orthogonal to
A. What's the vector? How do I do that?
How do I produce from this
vector a piece that's orthogonal to this
one? And the remember these vectors
might be in two dimensions or they might
be in 12
dimensions. I'm just looking for the
idea. So what's the idea? I Where did we
have
orthogonal a vector showing up that was
orthogonal to this guy?
Well, that was the first basic
calculation of the whole chapter. We we
did a
projection and the projection gave us
this part which was the part in the A
direction. Now the part we want is the
other part the E part th this part. This
is going to be our this is this is that
guy is that guy. This is our vector B.
That's that gives us that 90° angle. So
B is, you could say B is really what we
previously called
E, the the the error
vector. And and so and what is it? I
mean, what do I what is B here? A A is
A. No problem. B
is okay. What's this? What's this error
piece? Do you remember? It's it's I
start with the original
B and I take away
what it's projection. This
P this the vector B this error vector is
the original vector removing the
projection. So instead of wanting the
projection now that's what I want to
throw
away. I want to get the I want to get
the part that's perpendicular and there
will be a perpendicular part. it won't
be
zero because these vectors were
independent. So, so B, if B was along
the direction of A, then if the original
B and A were in the same direction, then
I'm I've only got one direction. But
here they're in two independent
directions and all I'm doing is getting
that guy. So, what's its
formula? What's the formula for that? If
I if I'm sub I want to subtract the
projection. So do you remember the
projection? It's some multiple of
a. And what's that multiple? It's it's
that thing we called X in the very very
first
lecture on this chapter. There's an
arpose a in the
bottom. And there's an a
transpose b. Isn't that
it? I think that's Graham's formula or
Graham Schmidt. No, that's Graham.
Schmidt has got to divide the whole
thing by the length. So he's just his
formula makes a mess which I'm not
willing to write down. So let's just see
that what am I saying here? I'm saying
that this vector B is perpendicular to
A. That these are orthogonal. A is
perpendicular to
B. Can you check that? How how do you
see that? Yes. Of course we our picture
is telling us yes we did it right. How
would I check that this matrix is
perpendicular to
A? I would multiply by A transpose and I
better get zero, right? I should have I
should check that a transpose B should
come out zero. So this is a transpose
times. Now what did we say B was? We
start with the original B and we take
away this projection.
And that should come out zero. Well,
here we get an arpose
b minus. And here is another arpose b
and the and it's an arpose a over arpose
a one. Those cancel and we do get zero.
Right
now, I
guess I can do numbers in there, but I
have to take a third vector to be sure
we've got this system down. So now I
have to say if I have independent
vectors A, B, and
C, I'm looking for orthogonal vectors A,
B, and capital C. And then of course the
third guy will just be C over its
length, the unit
vector. So this is now the
problem. I I I got B here.
I get a very
easily. And
now if you see the idea, we could figure
out a formula for for
C. So we So now that so this is like a
typical homework quiz problem. I give
you two vectors, you do this. I give you
three vectors and you have to make them
orthonormal.
So you do this again. The first vector
is fine. The second vector is
perpendicular to the first. And now I
need a third vector that's perpendicular
to the first one and the second one.
Right? That's that's this is the end of
the the lecture is to find this guy.
Find this vector this vector C that's
perpendicular. We at this point we know
A and
B, but C, the little C that we're given
is off in some oh, it's come, it's got
to come out of the blackboard to be
independent. So, so can I sort of draw
off? Off comes a C somewhere. I don't
know where am I going to put the darn
thing. Maybe I'll put
it off. Oh, I don't know. Like that
somehow. C. Little C.
And I already know that perpendicular
direction, that one and that one. So now
what's the idea? Give me the Graham
Schmidt formula for C. What is this C
here? Equals
what? What am I going to do? I'll start
with the given one as before, right? I
start with the vector I'm
given. And what do I do with it? I want
to remove out of it. I want to subtract
off. So, I'll put a minus sign in. I
want to subtract
off its components in the A, capital A,
and capital B directions. I just want to
get those out of there. Well, I know how
to do that. I did it with B. So I'll
just So let me let me take away. What if
I do
this? What have I
done? I've I've got little C and what
have I subtracted from
it? Its
component, its projection if you like in
the A direction.
And now I've got to subtract off its
component branspose C overpose B. That
multiple of B is its component in the B
direction. And that gives me the vector
capital C
that if if anything is if if there's any
justice this C should be perpendicular
to A and it should be perpendicular to
B and the only thing it's hasn't got is
unit vector. So we divide by its length
to to to get that too.
Okay, let me do a an example. Can
I let me I'll make my life easy. I'll
just take two vectors. So, let me do a
numerical example. If I'll give you two
vectors, you give me back the Graham
Schmidt orthonormal
basis and we'll see how to express that
in matrix form. Okay. So let me give you
the two
vectors. So So I'll take the vector A
equals let's say 1
one and B equals let's
say
0 2.
Okay. I
just I didn't want to cheat and make
them orthogonal in the first place
because then Graham Schmidt wouldn't be
needed. Okay, so those are not
orthogonal. So what is capital A? Well,
that that's the same as big A. That was
fine. What's
B? So B is this is the original B and
then I subtract off some multiple of the
A.
And what's the
multiple? What goes in
here? B here's the here's the A. This is
the this is the little B. This is the
big A. Also the little A. And I I want
to multiply it by that right that right
ratio which has a transpose A. Oh, here
here's my ratio. I'm just doing this.
So, it's a transpose b. What is a
transpose b? It looks like
three. And what is a Oh
my. What's a transpose a
three? I'm sorry. I didn't know that was
going to happen. Okay. But it happened.
Why should we knock it? Okay. So, so do
do you see it? All right. That's a
transpose b. There's arpose a. That's
the fraction. So, so I take this away
and I get one take away one is a zero. 0
minus this one is a minus one. And 2
minus the one is a
one. Okay. And what's this vector that
we finally found? This is
B. And how do I know it's right?
How do I know I've got a vector I want?
I check that B is perpendicular to that
A and B are perpendicular. That A is
perpendicular to B. Just look at that.
That one the dotproduct of that with
that is zero. Okay. So now what is my Q1
and
Q2? Why don't I put them in a
matrix? Of course, since I'm always
putting these, so the Q I'll put the Q1
and the Q2 in a matrix. And what are
they? Now, when I'm writing Q's, I've
I've I'm supposed to make things
normalized. I'm supposed to make things
unit vectors. So, I'm going to take that
A, but I'm going to divide it by
square<unk> of
3. And I'm going to take this B, but I'm
going to divide it by square<unk> of
two to make it a unit vector. And there
is my
matrix. That's my matrix with
orthonormal columns coming from Graham
Schmidt. And it comp sort of it it came
from the
original one
[Music]
one2, right? That was my original
guys. These were the two I started with.
These are the two that I'm happy to end
with because those are
orthonormal. So that's what Graham
Schmidt
did it and well tell me about the column
spaces of these
matrices. How is the column space of Q
related to the column space of A?
So I'm always asking you things like
this and that makes you think okay the
column space is all combinations of the
columns. It's that plane right? I've got
two vectors in three-dimensional space.
The column space is a
plane. The column space of this matrix
is a plane. What's the relation between
the
planes between the two column spaces?
They're one and the same, right? It's
the same column space. I didn't all I'm
taking is here this B
thing that I computed. This B thing that
I computed is a combination of B and A.
It and A was little A. So I'm always
working here with this in the same
space. I'm just like getting 90° angles
in there.
where my original column space had a
perfectly good basis, but it wasn't as
good as this
basis because it wasn't
orthonormal. Now, this one is
orthonormal and I have a basis then that
for so now projections all the
calculations I would ever want to do are
are a cinch with this orthonormal basis.
One final
point, one final point in this
chapter and it's the is it's just like
elimination. We we we learn how to do
elimination. We know all the steps. We
can do it. But
then I came back to it and said look at
it as a
matrix in matrix language and
elimination gave me what what was
elimination in matrix language I'll just
put it up there a was
lu that was matrix that was
elimination now I want to do the same
for Graham
Schmidt everybody who works in linear
algebra
isn't going to write out the columns are
orthogonal or orthonormal and isn't
going to write out these formulas.
They're going to write out the
connection between the matrix A and the
matrix
Q. And the two matrices have the same
column space, but there's some those
some matrix is taking and I'm going to
call it
R. So a equals QR is the magic
uh formula
here. It's the expression of Graham
Schmidt. And uh let me just let me just
uh capture that. So that's the my final
step then is A= QR. Maybe I can squeeze
it in
here. So A has columns. Let's say a1 and
a2. Let me suppose n is two just two
vectors.
Okay. So that's some combination of q1
and
q2
and times some matrix
r. They have the same column space.
This is just this matrix just includes
in it whatever these numbers like 3
over3 and 1 over<unk> 3 and 1 over<unk>2
probably that's probably that's what
it's got 1 over<unk> 3 1 over<unk> two
something there but actually it's got a
zero
there. So the the the main point about
um this a= qr is this this r turns out
to be upper triangular. It turns out
that this zero is upper
triangular. I could we could see
why. Let me see. I can put in general
formulas for what these are. This I
think in here should be the inner
product of a1 with q1.
And this one should
be be the inner product of A1 with
Q2 and that's what I believe is
zero. This will be something here and
this will be something here with uh
inner A1 transpose
Q2 sorry A2 transpose Q1 and A2
transpose Q2. But why is that guy
zero? Why is a1 Q2 zero? That's the
that's the key to this being this r here
being upper
triangular. You know why A1 Q2 is zero
because
A1 that was my this was this was really
A and B here. This was really A and B.
So this is a transpose Q2 and the whole
point of Graham Schmidt was that we
constructed these later Q's to be
perpendicular to the earlier vectors to
the earlier all the earlier vectors. So
that's why we get a triangular matrix.
the the so the
it's the result is
extremely
satisfactory that orthog that if I have
a matrix
with independent
columns that Graham Schmidt produces a
matrix with orthonormal columns and the
connection between those is a triangular
matrix.
That last point that the connection is a
triangular matrix. Please look in the
book. You have to see that one more
time. Okay. Thanks. That's great.